Be and now we'll do life again
and I think I'll do
a few more tonight like we do in the
scripture scenes. I'm going to Thailand in
December, we were there and we
studied refuge and I gave refuge to
loved ones for the first time in
many, many years.
I think 20 of them, gladly, in a large group
and everyone was excited and I
needed several powerful ones to see the names. I
really didn't sleep. MM and
Stanley helped me and no one got any
sleep and everyone was
happy. They got their refuge vows,
got their declaration.
We'll do it again according to the
scriptures and everyone felt.
Now I have my
Buddhist... I've taken so much...
Yes, you did it
or you didn't. That's
not about refuge.
So it's... If you're
sitting on the couch with your husband or wife, they
start yelling at each other and they... The
founder, Agena, and pardon,
Timm Busche, in the country...
You don't get refuge
if you get the bachelor's ceremony.
You, who gave the name...
That wasn't...  The real ceremony, the
real, the real refuge ceremony
happens at home on the couch when your
husband or your wife—what do you think you are?—says something bad to you.
You can consider yourself lucky
if a man or woman
says something bad to you because then you can
take refuge.
That's the moment you have to celebrate.
I took refuge.
What happened? My wife
texted me and I didn't say anything
because I know it's from me. You just took refuge.
You just took refuge. Whoever gave it to you,
you did it. And that's the
meaning of this meditation. Number
seven, a few candies, says that's the real
ritual. The real refuge ritual is that
you got your name on the
couch. It was stupid, okay, and you did
n't respond because you
understood that you don't want to experience it again next week,
and because the
people who are hurting you do
n't actually exist. And that is, that was
your refuge ceremony. And that's the
point that Paprika expresses, and in
meditation number 5, I want you to think about
bad moments in your
life.  And 6 should make you
proud.
7 should make you unhappy. What was
the most difficult moment in recent
years? Golf was the night my wife
told me you were really
bad with him,
and I was angry about it too, but then
I remembered that even
this person comes from me. I don't know
how I planned it,
probably from millions of lives, as
bad as I am now. He was, but
I was intelligent. I took refuge.
She said to me, and I did
n't defend myself. I didn't say
she wasn't right.
I didn't say shut up. I just
said I was going to
the bathroom, and I sat down,
and I thought about it for ten minutes.
How did I do that?
And then I calmed down, went back out,
and then we had dinner
together, and I took
refuge.
I had my refuge ceremony in
the bathroom. Understood this meditation.
Number 7,
you should think about a difficult time in
my life where you
reacted correctly. You reacted to yourself and
not incorrectly. Especially ex-
husbands, ex-wives, ex-girlfriends, ex-
bosses. It's real if you...
You can
do it with anyone, so in this meditation,
choose the most beautiful moments with
another person and forgive them
because they come from you. Let it go, and
then you have taken refuge in
forgiveness.